<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8' ?>
<!DOCTYPE book [
<!ENTITY % BOOK_ENTITIES SYSTEM "master.ent">
%BOOK_ENTITIES;
<!ENTITY % sgml.features "IGNORE">
<!ENTITY % xml.features "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % DOCBOOK_ENTS PUBLIC "-//OASIS//ENTITIES DocBook Character Entities V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/dbcentx.mod">
%DOCBOOK_ENTS;
]>
<book version="5.0" xml:lang="en-US" xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<?asciidoc-toc ?><?asciidoc-numbered ?>
	<info>
		<title>Release notes for Red Hat Developer Hub 1.0</title>
		<subtitle>What's new in Red Hat Developer Hub</subtitle>
		 <date>2023-11-20</date>
		<productname>Red Hat Developer Hub</productname>
		<productnumber>1.0</productnumber>
		<abstract>
			<para>
				This document contains release notes for Red Hat Developer Hub 1.0.
			</para>
		</abstract>
		<xi:include href="Author_Group.xml" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" />
		<xi:include href="Common_Content/Legal_Notice.xml" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" />
	</info>
	<preface xml:id="snip-conscious-language_install-rhdh">
		<title>Making open source more inclusive</title>
		<simpara>
			Red Hat is committed to replacing problematic language in our code, documentation, and web properties. We are beginning with these four terms: master, slave, blacklist, and whitelist. Because of the enormity of this endeavor, these changes will be implemented gradually over several upcoming releases. For more details, see <link xlink:href="https://www.redhat.com/en/blog/making-open-source-more-inclusive-eradicating-problematic-language"><emphasis>our CTO Chris Wright’s message</emphasis></link>.
		</simpara>
	</preface>
	<chapter remap="_release-notes-for-red-hat-developer-hub-1-0" xml:id="release-notes-for-red-hat-developer-hub-1-0">
		<title>Release Notes for Red Hat Developer Hub 1.0</title>
		<simpara>
			Red Hat Developer Hub 1.0 is a version of Backstage that Red Hat supports. It comes integrated with pre-built plug-ins, configuration settings, and deployment mechanisms, which enables you to streamline your end-to-end development environment.
		</simpara>
		<simpara>
			The Red Hat Developer Hub includes:
		</simpara>
		<itemizedlist>
			<listitem>
				<simpara>
					Software catalog to manage all your microservices, pipelines, and libraries
				</simpara>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<simpara>
					Plug-ins to expand the customizability and functionality
				</simpara>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<simpara>
					Tech Docs to create, maintain, and use technical documentation easily
				</simpara>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<simpara>
					Golden Path Templates (GPTs) to accelerate typical application development use cases
				</simpara>
			</listitem>
		</itemizedlist>
		<section remap="_about-this-release" xml:id="about-this-release">
			<title>About this release</title>
			<simpara>
				The release notes provide high-level coverage of the features that have been implemented in Red Hat Developer Hub 1.0 and document known issues in this release.
			</simpara>
			<simpara>
				Some features within this release may be available as a Technology Preview, providing access to upcoming product features, enabling customers to test functionality and to provide feedback during the development process.
			</simpara>
			<simpara>
				For more information about the support scope of Red Hat Technology Preview features, read <link xlink:href="https://access.redhat.com/support/offerings/techpreview">Technology Preview Support Scope</link>.
			</simpara>
		</section>
		<section remap="_notable-features" xml:id="notable-features">
			<title>Notable features</title>
			<simpara>
				The Red Hat Developer Hub 1.0 provides the following customization capabilities:
			</simpara>
			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
					<simpara>
						Ability to use Golden Path Templates (GPTs) that injects the best practices of an application development
					</simpara>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<simpara>
						Ability to customize technology radar, which helps you map out a tech strategy that keeps you ahead of the curve
					</simpara>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<simpara>
						Ability to customize your home page to highlight specific information
					</simpara>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
		</section>
		<section remap="_golden-path-templates-gpts" xml:id="golden-path-templates-gpts">
			<title>Golden Path Templates (GPTs)</title>
			<simpara>
				You use GPTs to create your opinionated and supported path to provision a resource, for example, build a backend service, launch a website, or create a data pipeline.
			</simpara>
		</section>
		<section xml:id="rhdh-technology-preview-features">
			<title>Technology Preview features</title>
			<important>
				<simpara>
					Technology Preview features are not supported with Red Hat production service-level agreements (SLAs) and might not be functionally complete. Red Hat does not recommend implementing any Technology Preview features in production environments. Technology Preview features provide early access to upcoming product innovations, enabling you to test functionality and provide feedback during the development process. For more information about support scope, see <link xlink:href="https://access.redhat.com/support/offerings/techpreview/">Technology Preview Features Support Scope</link>.
				</simpara>
			</important>
			<simpara>
				{ProductName} includes the following Technology Preview features:
			</simpara>
			<variablelist>
				<varlistentry>
					<term>Installation using the Red Hat Developer Hub Operator for Red Hat OpenShift</term>
					<listitem>
						<simpara>
							The Red Hat Developer Hub Operator wraps the Helm Chart to provide a simpler install process.
						</simpara>
					</listitem>
				</varlistentry>
			</variablelist>
		</section>
	</chapter>
</book>

